# Arjun Srinivasan

http://arjun010.github.io | arjun010@gatech.edu | +1-678-467-4938

## **EDUCATION**

## **GEORGIA TECH**

PhD. Computer Science

Specialization: Visual Analytics & Human-Computer Interaction May 2020 (expected)

## **GEORGIA TECH**

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

Specialization: Visual Analytics May 2016 | GPA: 3.84

#### **RV COLLEGE OF ENGG.**

B.E. Information Science July 2013 | GPA: 8.68/10.0

## **SKILLS**

#### MOST EXPERIENCED WITH:

Python • JavaScript • Java (Sun Certified) • SQL (Oracle Certified)

## **FAMILIAR WITH:**

R • C/C++ • node.is • C#

## FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES:

d3.js • NLTK • jQuery • Flask • scikit-learn • AngularJS

## **LEADERSHIP**

Salesforce.com Campus Brand Ambassador [2016-2017]

SAP Student Ambassador (1st student selected globally) [2013-2015]

Microsoft Student Partner [2011-2013]

# **RESEARCH OVERVIEW**

I design intelligent and expressive tools that combine multimodal input (e.g. speech and touch) and mixed-initiative recommendation techniques for human-data interaction. Specifically, my research leverages data visualization as a lens to support different aspects of data science including data cleaning and transformation, exploratory data analysis, and interpreting machine learning models.

## SUMMARY

Fourth year PhD student in Computer Science at Georgia Tech seeking full-time positions starting Summer 2020.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## MICROSOFT RESEARCH

#### RESEARCH INTERN

May 2016 - August 2016; May 2019 - August 2019 | Redmond, WA Developed multimodal data visualization interfaces and explored visual representation techniques to facilitate comparison in visualization dashboards.

#### **ADOBE RESEARCH**

#### RESEARCH INTERN

May 2018 - August 2018 | Seattle, WA

Developed algorithms and techniques to enhance discoverability of natural language commands in multimodal interfaces.

## SALESFORCE.COM

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

May 2015 - August 2015; May 2016 - August 2016 | San Francisco, CA Developed a visualization system for real-time monitoring and diagnosis of service queues across data centers in a multi-tenant cloud architecture

## SAP LABS INDIA

#### ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER

July 2013 - April 2014 | Bangalore, India

Worked on R&D of Business Process Integration solutions on the cloud.

# AWARDS / ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2018 College of Computing's "Outstanding Graduate Research Assistant"
- 2016 Winner of Salesforce.com Analytics Innovation Challenge
- 2015 Finalist of "The SAP IT Mobile App Competition 2015"
- 2014 National finalist of Walmart's "Collegiate Innovators Challenge"
- 2014 SAP Global Recognition Program Award for Teamwork
- 2013 Winner (1st place) of "SAP Osmosis 2013"
- 2012 Winner (1st runner-up) of "SAP BizTech India 2012"
- 2012 Winning developer at Microsoft's Windows 8 Hackathon
- 2011 National finalist of "SAP Dashboard Design Challenge India 2011"

# **SELECT PUBLICATIONS**

- Srinivasan, Arjun, et al. "Augmenting visualizations with interactive data facts to facilitate interpretation and communication." IEEE transactions on visualization and computer graphics 25.1 (2018): 672-681.
- Srinivasan, Arjun, et al. "Discovering natural language commands in multimodal interfaces." Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. ACM, 2019.
- Srinivasan, Arjun, and John Stasko. "Orko: Facilitating multimodal interaction for visual exploration and analysis of networks." IEEE transactions on visualization and computer graphics 24.1 (2017): 511-521.
- Srinivasan, Arjun, and John Stasko. "Natural language interfaces for data analysis with visualization: Considering what has and could be asked." Proceedings of the Eurographics/IEEE VGTC Conference on Visualization: Short Papers. Eurographics Association, 2017.